どうすんだよ ライダー
What do we do now, Rider?
What now, mad dog?
どうする 狂犬
Tokiomi...
時臣
I'll... kill you!
殺して やる
Saber!
セイバー
攻めあぐんでいるな
We aren't making much progress.
セイバーの左手が使えれば
If only we could use Saber's left arm...
Utw
Presents
Will one last miracle come to pass?
あと一度だけ奇跡は起こるだろう
Ato ichido dake kiseki wa okoru darou
A gentle voice paints a twisted future
優しい声で描く歪んだ未来
Yasashii koe de egaku yuganda mirai
For the sake of a world where nobody will cry
もう誰も泣かない世界のために
Mou dare mo nakanai sekai no tame ni
Before reaching the crimson-stained sky
赤く穢された空の何処にも
Akaku kegasareta sora no doko ni mo
My cries and prayers fade and disappear
届かず消える叫びと祈り
Todokazu kieru sakebi to inori
I can go on, abandoning all consolation
慰めは捨てて行ける
Nagusame wa sutete yukeru
The beautiful moonlight shines towards the beginning and vanishes
綺麗な月の光が始まりへと沈み行く
Kirei na tsuki no hikari ga hajimari e to shizumiyuku
Into the distance
その彼方へ
Sono kanata e
I'll continue to reach out as my eyes are gradually closed
閉ざされてく瞳でまだ遠くへ手を伸ばす
Tozasareteku hitomi de mada tooku e te wo nobasu
I believe in your sorrow
君の嘆きを 信じて
Kimi no nageki wo shinjite
おい セイバー
Hey, Saber!
This isn't working.
このままじゃ埒があかん
Withdraw!
いったん退け
Don't be ridiculous.
馬鹿を言うな
We must stop him here!
ここで食い止めなければ
But we've exhausted our options.
そうは言っても手詰まりであろうが
Fall back for now.
いいから退け
I have an idea.
余に考えがある
Listen, everyone.
いいか皆の衆 この先どういう策を講じるにしろ
Regardless of whatever plan we go with, we must first buy some time.
まずは時間稼ぎが必要だ
I shall draw him into Ionian Hetairoi.
ひとまず余が「王の軍勢」に奴を引きずり込む
However, even the combined forces of all my fierce warriors won't be able to destroy that.
とはいえ 余の精鋭たちが総出でも
アレを殺し尽くすのは無理であろう
Restraining him within the Reality Marble is the most we can do.
せいぜい固有結界の中で足止めするのが関の山だ
What then?
その後はどうする
No idea.
分からん
Huh?
If I take in a thing of that magnitude, the
Reality Marble will only last a few minutes.
あんなデカブツを取り込むとなれば
余の軍勢の結界が持つのはせいぜい数分が限度
You must find a way within that time.
その間にどうにかして
Heroic Spirits...
英霊たちよ 勝機を掴み得る策を見出してほしい
I want you to find a path to victory.
おい 坊主 貴様もこっちに残れ
Hey, boy.
You stay here too.
Hey...
いざ結界を展開したら 余には外の状況が解らなくなる
Once I activate the field, I won't know what transpires outside.
Boy, focus your mind and
call for me if anything happens.
坊主 何かあったら強く念じて余を呼べ
I will dispatch a messenger.
伝令を差し遣わす
セイバー ランサー
Saber! Lancer!
I'll leave the rest to you.
後は頼むぞ
うむ
Very well.
心得た
Such pointless struggling.
無駄な足掻きを
Mom!
お母さん
なんだ
What?
How about diving headfirst into that mass of filth, mongrel?
いっそ汚物に頭から突っ込んでみるというのはどうだ 雑種
あれだけ息巻いておきながら
After all that talk...
蓋を開けてみればこの体たらくか
This is all you have up your sleeve?
自滅する気か
Is he trying to kill himself?
Kariya.
雁夜
Think of this as my gift to you.
私からの恩情だと思え
「我が敵の火葬は苛烈なるべし」
Intensive Einäscherung.
Die an intensive fiery death.
I-I'll kill... you...
こ 殺してやる
時臣
Tokiomi!
Zouken...
What now?
どうする
時間稼ぎとか言われても
He's buying us time, but if we can't use it to come up with anything, we'll be right back where we started.
その間に僕らが何も思いつかなかったら
結局は元の木阿弥だ
Hey, Einzbern...
なあおい アインツベルン 何かいい手はないのかよ
Got any ideas?
Hey!
なあってば
Well, um...
ええと あの
これ どうするのかしら
How does this work?
アイリか
Iri?
No, I'm...
いや 僕は じゃなくて
I mean...
そうか ライダーのマスターだな
I see.
You must be Rider's Master.
ちょうどいい お前にも話がある
Perfect.
I wanted to talk to you too.
Who are you?
だ 誰だアンタは
そんなことはいい
It doesn't matter.
Caster's disappearance was the work of your Servant, yes?
キャスターを消したのはお前のサーヴァントの仕業だな
そうだけど 一応
That's right, I guess.
Question.
質問だ
When Rider releases his Reality Marble, can he position its contents at a particular location?
ライダーの固有結界 あれを解除した時に中身を狙った場所に落とせるか
ある程度 せいぜい100メートルかそこらの範囲だと思うが
To a degree.
Within a hundred meters or so, but it's possible.
可能なはずだ
外に再出現する時の主導権はライダーにあるだろうから
Rider should be able to control where it will materialize.
Very well.
いいだろう
I'll wait for the right moment and fire a signal flare then.
後で僕がタイミングを見計らって信号弾を打ち上げる
Release Caster right under it.
その真下でキャスターを解放しろ
Can you do that?
できるな
I can... I think.
できる と思う たぶん
Probably.
One more thing.
もう一つ
I need you to relay a message to Lancer.
その場にいるランサーに言ってやれ
Tell him Saber's left arm holds an anti-fortress Noble Phantasm.
セイバーの左手には対城宝具があるとな
Huh?
どうかしたのか
Is something wrong?
Well, he had a message for you.
それが あんたに言伝があった
Something about Saber's left arm
being an anti-fortress Noble Phantasm...
「セイバーの左手は対城宝具」だとか何とか
本当なのか セイバー
Is that true, Saber?
それは キャスターのあの怪物を 一撃で仕留め得るものなのか
Can it destroy Caster's monster with a single strike?
可能だろう
It can.
だが ランサー
However, Lancer.
The weight of my sword is the weight of my pride.
我が剣の重さは誇りの重さだ
貴方と戦った結果の傷は 誉れであっても枷ではない
The wound from my battle with you is an honor, not a fetter.
The aid of Diarmuid O'Dyna as a substitute
for my left arm is worth ten thousand men.
この左手の代替にディルムッド·オディナの助勢を得るなら
それこそが万軍に値する
なあセイバー 俺はあのキャスターが赦せない
Well, Saber.
I cannot forgive Caster's actions.
奴は諸人の絶望を是とし
He affirms the despair of those around him and finds joy in spreading terror.
恐怖の伝播を悦とする者
By the vows I swore as a knight, I cannot abide such evil.
騎士の誓いに賭けて
あれは看過できぬ「悪」だ
Lancer, you mustn't!
ランサー それは駄目だ
Is it Saber who must win this fight? Is it Lancer?
いま勝たなければならないのは セイバーか ランサーか
No, it is neither.
いや どちらでもない
What must triumph here is the knight's path of chivalry that we champion.
ここで勝利するべきは 我らが奉じた「騎士の道」
Is that not so, Heroic Spirit Arturia?
そうだろう
英霊アルトリアよ
ランサー
Lancer...
I rest my hopes for victory
upon your blade, King of Knights.
我が勝利の悲願を 騎士王の一刀に託す
頼んだぞ セイバー
I'm counting on you, Saber.
請け合おう ランサー
I accept, Lancer.
Upon my sword, I promise you victory!
今こそ我が剣に勝利を誓う
あれが
That's from the legend of King Arthur...
アーサー王伝説の
Saber!
セイバー
Berserker?
バーサーカー
What is he...?
アイツ
雑種の分際でオレに背を向けるか
You dare turn your back on me, mongrel?
You insult me!
不敬な
何
What?!
Saber!
セイバー
What's the matter with Berserker?!
何なんだよ バーサーカーの奴
Just when I had finally regained the use of my left arm...
ようやく左手を取り戻した矢先に
A soul naturally seeks pleasure, consciously or not.
自覚がなくとも魂というものは本能的に愉悦を追い求める
He was the only one you ordered Assassin to investigate to such a
degree that you could understand those "complicated circumstances".
お前はこの男についてのみ
入り組んだ事情が見えてくるほどの調査をアサシンに強要してしまったのだ
And this was all due to your unconscious interest.
お前自身の無自覚な興味によってな
It's still too soon.
まだ早い
That shaking...
今の震動は
ライダーの固有結界が
It's a sign Rider's Reality Marble can't hold on much longer.
限界に近づいている予兆だろう
Rider...
ライダー
新衛隊が一人 ミトリネス
I am Mithrenes, of the Hetairoi.
I have come as the king's ears.
王の耳に成り代わりて 馳せ参じてございます
こ これから合図を待って
I-I want him to wait for the signal, and then release
Caster from the Reality Marble at the indicated point.
指定された場所にキャスターを放り出せるように結界を解いてほしい
Can he do that?
できるな
可能ですが
It's possible, but we're running out of time.
事は一刻を争います
Our forces within the Reality Marble cannot restrain that sea monster much longer.
すでに結界内の我らが軍勢は
あの海魔めを足止めし続けることが叶いそうになく
分かってる 分かってるんだよ
I know!
I know that!
畜生 バーサーカーの奴
Damn it!
Damn that Berserker.
アイツ何とかならないのか
Can't we do something about him?
I will go.
俺が行こう
ランサー
Lancer...
That's enough, mad warrior!
そこまでにしてもらうぞ 狂戦士
It's all or nothing!
一か八か
Archer...
アーチャー
That's it!
あれだ あの真下
Right under that!
御意
As you wish.
Honestly...
ったく 一体何を手間取って
What took so long?
Now, Saber. Show me.
さあセイバーよ 示すがいい
お前の英霊としての輝きの真価
I shall judge the true worth of your brilliance as a Heroic Spirit.
このオレが見定めてやる
The light...
光りが
輝ける
Her sword shines, a dream that all warriors
scattered in battle, past, present and future,
かの剣こそは
過去 現在 未来を通じ
戦場に散っていくすべての兵たちが
hold and mournfully exalt as their final moments approach.
今際のきわに懐く哀しくも尊きユメ
その意志を誇りと掲げ
She carries their will as her pride, bidding them to remain steadfast in their loyalty.
その信義を貫けと糾し
Now, the undefeated king sings aloud the
name of the miracle she holds in her hands.
いま常勝の王は高らかに 手に執る奇跡の真名を謳う
其は
Its name is...
約束された勝利の剣
Excalibur!
This light...
この光は
There's no doubt.
間違いない この光は
This was the brilliance that blessed Jeanne and me with joy and bliss...
ジャンヌと共に歓喜の祝福を得た輝き
What...
私は 一体
...have I...
Did you see that, King of Conquerors?
見届けたか 征服王
That was Saber's brilliance.
あれがセイバーの輝きだ
Do you still refuse to accept her, having witnessed light of such magnitude?
あれだけの光を魅せられてもなお
お前は奴を認めぬのか
That light comes from her having taken all her people's hopes upon herself.
時代の民草の希望を一身に引き受けたが故の あの威光
Its brightness is what makes it tragic.
眩しいが故に痛々しいわ
あんなものを背負わされたのが
Especially when you consider the one bearing that burden is just a dreaming little girl.
ただの夢見る小娘だったと知ってはな
そんな娘が 蝶よ花よと愛でられることも
The girl never had a happy childhood, never fell in love,
恋に焦がれることもなく
but was cursed by her ideals and ended up this way.
「理想」などという呪いに憑かれた果ての姿があれだ
痛ましくて見るに耐えん
It is too painful to look upon.
Isn't that what makes her so beautiful?
なればこそ 愛いではないか
アレが懐いていた身に余る理想は
Her dreams were too much for her.
I imagine they destroyed the dreamer herself in the end.
きっと最後には懐いた当人をも焼き果たしたに違いない
その散り際の慟哭の涙
The tears of lamentation she shed during her final
moments must have been quite sweet to the taste.
舐めればさぞ甘かったであろうな
やはり貴様とは相容れぬな
You and I just can't see eye to eye, Babylonian King of Heroes.
バビロニアの英雄王
Oh?
ほう 今更になって察したか
So you finally realized?
Then what will you do, Rider?
ならば如何とする ライダー
その怒り 今すぐにでも武をもって示すか
Will you let your steel give shape to your rage?
それが出来れば痛快であろうが
I would like that very much,
but I have exerted myself a little too much tonight to face an opponent like you.
貴様を相手の戦となると
今宵の余は些さか以上に消耗しすぎとる
Of course, I would have to fight back
should you refuse to allow me passage.
無論 見逃す手はないと突っかかって来るならば
相手にせんわけにもいかんがな
構わぬ
I don't mind.
You may flee, King of Conquerors.
逃亡を許すぞ 征服王
お前は十全の状態で潰さねば
It wouldn't satisfy me to destroy you
at anything less than your full strength.
オレの気も収まらぬ
さては貴様もあの黒いのに撃ち落されたダメージが残っておるな
So, you're wounded yourself from
being shot down by that black thing.
オレは挑発には死を以て遇するぞ
I repay provocation with death.
We'll decide this next time, King of Heroes.
次に持ち越しだ 英雄王
Our battle shall be the one that
determines the winner of this Grail War.
我らの対決は即ち聖杯戦争の覇者を決する大一番となることだろう
果たして どうかな
I wouldn't be so sure.
I have yet to decide whether only one individual is worthy of receiving my treasure, Rider.
我ガ至宝を賜わすに値するのが一人のみだとは
まだオレは決めていないぞ ライダー
人の領分を超えた悲願に手を伸ばす愚か者
She is a fool who reaches for dreams beyond human attainment.
I, Gilgamesh, am the only one in this Heaven and Earth with the right to love her in her destruction.
その破滅を愛してやれるのは天上天下ただ一人
このギルガメッシュをおいて他にはない
Ephemeral and brilliant one, fall to my embrace.
儚くも眩しき者よ
我が腕に抱かれるがいい
それがオレの決定だ
That is my decision.
Episode 15
Golden Brilliance
Doushite sora wa konnani aokute
どうして空はこんなに青くて
Why is the sky so blue?
Nanimo kanashimi wo shiranu you ni
何も悲しみを知らぬように
As if oblivious to sadness
Itsumo tamerawazu ashita e to kuzureochiru
いつも躊躇わず明日へと崩れ落ちる
It crumbles incessantly to make way for a new day
Inochi wa tarinai mama umarete kuru no ne
命は足りないまま生まれてくるのね
I suppose we are born with our lives short
Kakeochita kokoro ni anata ga furete
かけおちた心にあなたが触れて
You have touched my torn heart
Futari de yuku mirai wa kegare no nai tsuyosa de
二人で行く未来は穢れのない強さで
Our future ahead is filled with a pure, unblemished strength
Sora wa takaku kaze wa utau
空は高く 風は歌う
The sky is vast, the wind is melody
Yume wo miteta yorokobi e to
夢を見てた喜びへと
Men will one day come to realize
Hito wa itsuka tadoritsukeru
人はいつか辿り着ける
The joy of chasing after a dream
Kodomo no hitomi de anata wa shinjita
子供の瞳であなたは信じた
With the eyes of a child, you've always had faith
Soba ni iru yo
そばにいるよ
I'll be right beside you
Kooritsuita mori wo nukete
凍りついた森を抜けて
As we pass through the frozen forest
Sono hitomi ga sekai no nageki ni mayowanu you ni
その瞳が世界の嘆きに迷わぬように
So that the world's sorrow will not taint your eyes
フィオナ騎士団が一番槍 ディルムッド·オディナ
I am Diarmuid O'Dyna, first spear of the Knights of Fianna.
俺は お前と出会えてよかった
I am glad to have met you!
Splendid!
応とも ブリテン王アルトリア·ペンドラゴンが受けて立つ
I, Arturia Pendragon, King of Britain, accept your challenge.
いざ
Come!
Next Episode
Terminus of Honor
Here I come!
推して参る